<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AJTRE</title>
    <link>https://www.ajtre.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AJTRE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ajtre.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A critical step in applying a computational approach for drug discovery under the new outbreak situation</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/a-critical-step-in-applying-a-computational-approach-for-drug-discovery-under-the-new-outbreak-situation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/a-critical-step-in-applying-a-computational-approach-for-drug-discovery-under-the-new-outbreak-situation/</guid>
      <description>An awareness of uncorrelated and correlated results between in silico and in vitro studies from the identification of enzyme inhibitors. The urgency of the drug discovery against viral infection is raising after the emergence of 2019 new coronavirus epidemic in China. The traditional drug discovery requires years of operation. Therefore, the fast-track strategy has been proceeded by applying a computer-based approach. However, the correlation between this approach and its biological activity is a great concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-cancer property from a Thai medicinal plant</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/anti-cancer-property-from-a-thai-medicinal-plant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/anti-cancer-property-from-a-thai-medicinal-plant/</guid>
      <description>Oxyresveratrol: Anti-cancer breast cancer and the mechanism of actions Oxyresveratrol poses potent cytotoxicity to several kinds of cancer cells. The compound moderated various molecular alterations of breast cancer cells including apoptosis, cell proliferation, metastasis and cancer repair pathways. Interestingly, Oxyresveratrol down-regulates RAD51 and genes in homologous recombination, which breaks the mechanism of self-repair resulting in overcoming the drug resistance.
 * corresponding author (SR: S.Radapong@2017.ljmu.ac.uk, KJR: K.J.Ritchie@ljmu.ac.uk)
Received: 21 March 2020, Accepted: 30 May 2020, Published: 31 December 2020</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atmospheric Water Generator</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/atmospheric-water-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/atmospheric-water-generator/</guid>
      <description>Water extraction from ambient air by using a Desiccant Based Atmospheric Water Generator There are still many places in the world where safe drinkable water is not available. The reason mostly lies in not having enough freshwater resources and the cleanliness of the water. In order to solve these problems, an atmospheric water generator serves to produce clean potable water by using the concept of extracting water vapour from the air and condensing it into liquid water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Brain Tumour Regions Segmentation Using Modified U-Net</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/automatic-brain-tumour-regions-segmentation-using-modified-u-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/automatic-brain-tumour-regions-segmentation-using-modified-u-net/</guid>
      <description>Early diagnosis is an important key for brain tumour patients&#39; survival. The segmentation of the tumour regions is done manually by the experts and it is time-consuming. In this work, we present a novel network architecture that automatically segments the whole tumour regions and intra-tumour structures (edema, enhancing tumour, necrotic and non-enhancing tumour). We evaluated the results using dice similarity coefficient and obtained promising results.
 * corresponding author (keerati.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperativity in non-covalent metallophilic Pt···Pt interaction of aggregated square-planar Pt(II) complexes bearing isoquinolinyl pyrazolate; Theoretical insights</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/cooperativity-in-non-covalent-metallophilic-ptpt-interaction-of-aggregated-square-planar-ptii-complexes-bearing-isoquinolinyl-pyrazolate-theoretical-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/cooperativity-in-non-covalent-metallophilic-ptpt-interaction-of-aggregated-square-planar-ptii-complexes-bearing-isoquinolinyl-pyrazolate-theoretical-insights/</guid>
      <description>Pt···Pt contacts are more evident in the trimer aggregates rather than in the dimer ones, and especially in the case of the T1 optimized geometries. Esyn and E-EA values indicate a positive synergy between both interactions which is in good agreement with the shortening of the equilibrium distance in T1 state. The EDA reveals that the ∆Etot of trimer Pt1a is controlled by the ∆Eele and ∆Edisp terms.
 * corresponding authors (NK: naweekung@gmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Macro Uncertainty on Subjective Uncertainty and Mean Expectation</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/effects-of-macro-uncertainty-on-subjective-uncertainty-and-mean-expectation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/effects-of-macro-uncertainty-on-subjective-uncertainty-and-mean-expectation/</guid>
      <description>The empirical study of the macro uncertainty’s effect on subjective uncertainty and mean expectation using datasets of households and professional forecasters Macro uncertainty affects the assessed probabilistic distribution of individual economic forecasts. In this study, we empirically document the effects of macro uncertainty on subjective uncertainty (second moment) and mean expectation (first moment) of GDP growth and income forecasts. Based on the four datasets of households and professional forecasters, our results show that macro uncertainty does not always increase subjective uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of volatile organic compounds by use of Field Asymmetric Ion Mobility Spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/identification-of-volatile-organic-compounds-by-use-of-field-asymmetric-ion-mobility-spectrometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/identification-of-volatile-organic-compounds-by-use-of-field-asymmetric-ion-mobility-spectrometry/</guid>
      <description>Field Asymmetric Ion Mobility Spectrometer (FAIMS) provides rapid (30 seconds for a sample) analysis under atmospheric pressure.
 * corresponding author (chantipmanee.n@hotmail.com)
Received: 28 February 2020, Accepted: 06 June 2020, Published: 31 December 2020
DOI: 10.5281/zenodo.4383331 | 📁 view PDF file
Background Field Asymmetric Ion Mobility Spectrometry (FAIMS) is one of the Ion Mobility Spectrometry (IMS) techniques. FAIMS is a very sensitive technique that can identify gaseous phase ions under atmospheric pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Inpainting with Variational Autoencoders</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/image-inpainting-with-variational-autoencoders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/image-inpainting-with-variational-autoencoders/</guid>
      <description>Restoring corrupted image with Variational Autoencoders, a machine learning technique This work presents the training methodology of variational autoencoder in order to restore the missing part of a corrupted image and question the requirement of homogeneity in the implementation and difference situation of corrupted data.
 * corresponding author (cg226@stud.uni-heidelberg.de)
Received: 01 March 2020, Accepted: 09 June 2020, Published: 31 December 2020
DOI: 10.5281/zenodo.4383315 | 📁 view PDF file</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating a challenge of building a superconducting quantum computer</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/investigating-a-challenge-of-building-a-superconducting-quantum-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/investigating-a-challenge-of-building-a-superconducting-quantum-computer/</guid>
      <description>Probing two-level systems with a surface acoustic wave resonator Parasitic two-level systems (TLS) coupling to a superconducting quantum circuit causes information loss. To mitigate this problem, a better physical understanding of the coupling mechanism is crucial. Phase noise caused by TLS interaction is investigated by using a surface acoustic wave resonator. The results show a significant correlation of resonance frequency fluctuations between different resonance modes, supporting the prediction of the TLS model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learnt from Impact to World’s Aviation due to Covid-19</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/lessons-learnt-from-impact-to-worlds-aviation-due-to-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/lessons-learnt-from-impact-to-worlds-aviation-due-to-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>The world’s aviation industry had been skyrocketing for the past decades. The demand for new aircraft was so high that airlines complained to Airbus for failing to deliver aircraft on time. Suddenly right after Chinese New Year this year, the world of aviation has collapsed nearly completely. However, there are at least five key lessons the world of aviation has learnt from their biggest crisis in history.
 Received: 29 February 2020, Accepted: 05 July 2020, Published: 31 December 2020</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein extraction from Rice bran</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/protein-extraction-from-rice-bran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/protein-extraction-from-rice-bran/</guid>
      <description>The extraction of protein from plants using the cellulase enzyme. In addition, the extracted proteins were characterized including, protein solubility, proximate analysis, Fourier transform infrared spectrometer (FTIR), SDS-pages, emulsifying and foaming. Rice bran is a by-product of the rice milling process, which is classified as a waste. However, there has been research done earlier; found that rice bran contains a massive number of proteins when compared to other plants. The extraction of plant proteins using cellulase enzymes is considered because the great nutrition is revealed, in which there is a comparison of extraction in many circumstances to get the best conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Online Defamatory and Insulting Speech under Thai Law</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/regulating-online-defamatory-and-insulting-speech-under-thai-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/regulating-online-defamatory-and-insulting-speech-under-thai-law/</guid>
      <description>The Suitability of the Thai laws of Defamation and Insult to Regulate Speech Online The Internet allows us to freely express ideas more than other types of communication. Some online speech may impact a personality right. Law should strike a fair balance between preserving the freedom of speech and providing the protection to a personality right. Thai law protects personality rights by the laws which were enacted before the Internet period; thus, it is unclear whether these laws are suitable for regulating online speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk assessment of a self-tracking EM-integrated fetoscope</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/risk-assessment-of-a-self-tracking-em-integrated-fetoscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/risk-assessment-of-a-self-tracking-em-integrated-fetoscope/</guid>
      <description>Embedding an electromagnetic (EM) sensing at the tip of a fetoscope is appealing as it would allow to record the position and orientation of the tip of the fetoscope in real time. This tracking information may be useful for advanced guidance schemes that may help the surgeon during the intervention. However, adding such an EM-sensor should be done with great care as it may lead to additional risks for the patients (mother and fetus), the surgeon or the fetoscope itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The residential site environmental preferences of older adults in a rural Asian context from a case study of a village in Northern Thailand</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/the-residential-site-environmental-preferences-of-older-adults-in-a-rural-asian-context-from-a-case-study-of-a-village-in-northern-thailand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/the-residential-site-environmental-preferences-of-older-adults-in-a-rural-asian-context-from-a-case-study-of-a-village-in-northern-thailand/</guid>
      <description>This study examines elders’ preferences for residential site environments from their perceptions and evaluations. Unlike most earlier works on environments for elders, the study focuses on residential sites in a rural Asian context, with a mixed-methodology based on the extent of Person-Environment (P–E) fit. This will help to understand and identify the preferences of residential site environmental characteristics in a rural context.
 * corresponding author (axh798@student.bham.ac.uk, alisa.hthong@gmail.com)
Received: 04 February 2020, Accepted: 10 June 2020, Published: 31 December 2020</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xanthine Oxidoreductase Mediates Nitrite-Induced Platelet Inhibition</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/xanthine-oxidoreductase-mediates-nitrite-induced-platelet-inhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/post/2020/12/31/xanthine-oxidoreductase-mediates-nitrite-induced-platelet-inhibition/</guid>
      <description>Nitrite reduction by Xanthine Oxidoreductase modulates platelet reactivity and in part mediates platelet inhibition by inorganic nitrate in mice Xanthine oxidoreductase (XOR) is a potential missing link in platelet hyperactivity and cardiovascular diseases. Bioconversion of NO2- to NO by XOR modulates platelet reactivity as we observed rises in plasma NO2- levels after Xdh allele deletion in mice. This higher plasma NO2- in Xdh heterozygous mice was associated with greater platelet reactivity demonstrated in a tail bleeding, thrombus formation, and platelet aggregation study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Journal for Thai Researchers in Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.ajtre.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ajtre.org/about/</guid>
      <description>ISSN: 2730-2784 Volume 1 | Issue 1 was published on 31 December 2020
This journal is publicly available and can be accessed without any charge.
EDITORIAL  Editor-in-chief: Kridsadakorn Chaichoompu ℹ️ Chief journal editor: Issara Orikasa Managing editors: Tanut Ungwattanapanit, Sittichoke Som-am, Piyapat Saranrittichai, Nad Siroros  PUBLISHING  Management: Kridsadakorn Chaichoompu ℹ️ Journal: Issara Orikasa Website: Teerat Pitakrat, Piyapat Saranrittichai  MANAGEMENT  Chief supervisor: Manop Sittidech Supervisor: Thanakorn Chanmalee, Jaturong Amonchaisup Administration: Siriluk Pumirat, Puracheth Rithchumpon, Sirasak Tepjit Event: Puracheth Rithchumpon, Arada Jamnongpipatkul, Sittichoke Som-am, Nad Siroros, Piyapat Saranrittichai, Kanthanakorn Noysena, Sirasak Tepjit, Kridsadakorn Chaichoompu ℹ️ Public Relations: Jompoj Wongphechauxsorn, Nad Siroros, Arada Jamnongpipatkul, Puracheth Rithchumpon, Atiruj Jerddeesakul Graphic: Atiruj Jerddeesakul, Issara Orikasa  MANAGEMENT OFFICE Office of Science and Technology, Royal Thai Embassy, Brussels, Belgium.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
